gratispoints.com 2014-07-02

# GratisPoints

Last updated: 17/4/2013

GratisPoints is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. GratisPoints is a branded site owned and operated by United Sample Inc., headquartered at 16501 Ventura Blvd., Suite 250, Encino, California, 91436, with its United Kingdom office located at 88 Gray’s Inn Road, London, WC1X 8AA. 

Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our website and services. By using this website and registering for our service you agree that your personal information will be shared with United Sample Inc. in the U.S., where a lower level of privacy protection may apply than in your own country.

What personally identifiable information does GratisPoints collect from me?

GratisPoints collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of websites.

Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, GratisPoints asks for your name, email address, zip code, household information and personal interests. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register, you are no longer anonymous to GratisPoints and you can access the various protected areas of the site.  
For a more detailed discussion about the collection of data through cookies, please see the section immediately below.

What are cookies and how does GratisPoints use them?

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, GratisPoints may use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. Some areas on GratisPoints where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable may require that you accept cookies. This avoids you having to enter your login information many times in one day.

Currently, cookies are utilized by GratisPoints within the following four primary categories 1) business cookies which operate as a quality control and verification mechanism in connection with the survey process; (2) performance cookies which enable traffic patterns and uses on the GratisPoints website to be measured and optimized; (3) user cookies which allow user information to be recorded so as to enhance performance and user experience on the website; and 4) targeting cookies which are utilized to measure web viewing for market research purposes.

If you do not wish to have your activity and browsing behaviour tracked by GratisPoints, you may opt out by contacting our customer support team at support@surveyhelpcenter.com or selecting the opt-out button located on the “My Account” page. You can opt-out from the setting of such cookies by changing your settings within your browser. Furthermore you can set-up your browser so that the browser is asking you each time before a cookie is dropped on your device. Also you can delete all you cookies on your device within you browser. You can find all information about cookies, browser settings and cookie deletion on http://www.allaboutcookies.org/   
If you have further question with regards to cookie settings please contact support@surveyhelpcenter.com 

In addition, from time to time, tracking mechanisms such as cookies or web beacons may be used by third party content and advertisements which you may choose to view while being on the GratisPoints site. You should review the privacy policies of the websites serving this content, as they may allow for the gathering of information to serve advertising on multiple third party websites over which GratisPoints has no control. Please consult the privacy policies of such third party websites for more information.

Who is collecting information and for what purpose?

GratisPoints collects valuable information, which assists in developing new products and services. When you are on an GratisPoints site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with GratisPoints or with any other third party with whom you elect to share such information, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than GratisPoints, the use of your data and personal information will be governed by appropriate confidentiality and security agreements between GratisPoints and such third parties. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service or by electing not to participate in any given survey. 

Promotions that run on GratisPoints may be sponsored by companies other than GratisPoints or may be co-sponsored by GratisPoints and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you do not want your data to be shared.

Any Sensitive Information (i.e. personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual) will be treated with additional care. If GratisPoints intends to disclose such information to a third party or to use it for a purpose other than that for which it was originally collected, you will be expressly asked permission prior to any such disclosure or use.

Please be aware that GratisPoints advertisers or websites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you when you visit them. The information practices of those websites linked to GratisPoints are not covered by this privacy statement. Please consult the privacy policies of such third party websites for more information.

With whom does GratisPoints share my information?

As a general rule, GratisPoints will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or User Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

Business Partners & Sponsors: GratisPoints may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. If any personal data about you were ever to be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give GratisPoints permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfil your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information is going to be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer. 

Third Party Data & Aggregate Data: Under confidentiality agreements, GratisPoints may match user information with third party data. Also, GratisPoints discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

Other: GratisPoints may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating GratisPoints’s Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) GratisPoints’s rights or property, other GratisPoints users or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. GratisPoints may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service and improve our products and services.

Finally, if there is a sale of a majority of the shares or assets of the legal entities owning and operating GratisPoints, you agree that your personal information and data may be transferred or assigned to such new owners.

Children under the age of 13

Because this website and its surveys are not directed at children under the age of 13, we do not provide memberships to persons under 13. If you are under the age of 13, please let your parent or guardian know about this policy and get his or her permission before you give us any of your personal information or demographic information, use our website or participate in surveys. Except as may be required by law, United Sample will not knowingly collect, maintain or disclose any personal information from children under the age of 13 without the parent’s express approval and consent.  
General information regarding minors   
In some jurisdictions, participation in GratisPoints, its surveys, and other offerings are subject to age restrictions and other limitations with regard to persons up to the age of 18. Please consult your local requirements, but if you have a specific question or query, please contact: support@surveyhelpcenter.com. 

Information for Parents/Guardians

If you are a parent or guardian who has discovered that your child has submitted his or her personal information without your permission or consent, United Sample will take reasonable steps to remove that information from the its database at your request. To request removal of your child’s information, please send us an e-mail at support@surveyhelpcenter.com and be sure to include in your message the same user name, password, and e-mail address that your child submitted.

What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt to receive information from these third parties, GratisPoints will share your name and email address with them. 

Only GratisPoints (or agents working on behalf of GratisPoints and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you have indicated that you do not object to these offers.

As indicated above, you also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies.

What is GratisPoints’s policy on allowing me to update or correct my personally identifiable information?

You may edit your GratisPoints Account Information and your public GratisPoints Profile at any time by using your GratisPoints ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click here.

Your GratisPoints account can be deactivated. Please contact support@surveyhelpcenter.com for further instructions about deactivating your GratisPoints account.

Anyone can request access to or rectification of his or her other personal information collected and used by GratisPoints by contacting us at support@surveyhelpcenter.com. Note that your request must be sufficiently precise and a proof of identity will be required.

Are there limits to the number of surveys I can complete?

To ensure that high research standards are met for our clients and the general public, United Sample places, at its sole discretion, an upper limit on the number of surveys a respondent can complete during a given time period (a week or a day). This limit, which is set at the reasonable discretion of United Sample, is based on a variety of factors and these are subject to change.

What other requirements or obligations are placed on me?

The time you spend to participate in surveys and other offerings on of our websites and other platforms (including mobile) provides valuable feedback to our clients which helps result in better products and services in the marketplace. In return for your participation, you earn points towards various awards and also have opportunities for other offerings and prizes. You are solely responsible for the use, purchase and maintenance of your own electronic devices (be they handheld devices, laptops, etc.) and all of the corresponding internet connection, landline, wireless carrier, or other charges that you may incur regarding the use of such devices. You also agree that you will not participate in surveys while operating a moving vehicle, or in any other unsafe situation. You release GratisPoints, the survey sponsors, their officers, directors, employees or their affiliates from any claim of damages arising from, or relating to, your response(s) to the notifications on your mobile device and/or while taking a mobile survey.

Can I receive surveys on my mobile devices? 

In addition to websites, some GratisPoints surveys and solutions are offered via mobile devices. You will participate in such surveys only to the extent you expressly agree to participate through this platform. You acknowledge and agree that in such circumstances, mobile tracking functions will be enabled which track your mobile device via position locaters such as Global Positioning System (“GPS”) for the purpose of providing you with customized and timely surveys or related services and initiatives which are tailored to query and/or measure your specific preferences and/or opinions and to provide the most meaningful and timely information to GratisPoints clients and partners. After participating in these offerings, you can elect to opt out at any time. 

When you are participating in GratisPoints surveys and solutions via mobile devices and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with GratisPoints or with any other third party with whom you elect to share such information, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. If personally identifiable information is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than GratisPoints, the use of such personal information will be governed by appropriate confidentiality and security agreements between GratisPoints and such third parties. Because GratisPoints surveys and solutions via mobile devices are not directed to children under the age of 13, we do not provide memberships to persons under age 13 for that purpose. Any surveys or solutions via mobile devices are further subject to the requirements set forth in the section above, entitled, “Children under the age of 13”, of this Privacy Policy.

There may be instances when photographs, video or other imagery of individuals or locations is captured via mobile devices in connection with surveys and other solutions (the “Imagery”). GratisPoints will not utilize the rights of publicity of any individual in connection with the Imagery (or otherwise) without obtaining the proper consents. Any use by you of any Imagery should be utilized for your internal purposes only and any required consents from third parties must be properly obtained. You agree to indemnify and hold harmless United Sample, Inc., its branches, subsidiaries, affiliates, officers, directors, employees and agents from any claims arising out of, or relating to, your unauthorized use of the Imagery.

Please be aware that other websites and apps may collect personally identifiable information about you when you visit or use them. The information practices of those websites and apps linked to GratisPoints are not covered by this privacy statement. Please consult the privacy policies of such third party websites or apps for more information.

What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of my information?

Your GratisPoints Account Information and GratisPoints Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. GratisPoints will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your GratisPoints account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

Whenever GratisPoints handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, GratisPoints takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, GratisPoints cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

Finally, in the event that there are material changes to this policy in the future, GratisPoints will make appropriate announcements and disclosures on this website.
